How are you feeling today?
你今天感觉怎么样？
Often when we ask people that question, they reply ‘not bad’, or ‘could be worse’.
当我们问别人这个问题时，得到的回答往往是“还不错”或者“不算太糟”。
But what would make us feel ‘perfect’?
但什么才能让我们感觉“完美”呢？
Maybe we could live better by being healthier, less stressed, more motivated – but how?
或许更健康的身体、更小的压力、更足的干劲能让生活变得更好——但具体该怎么做呢？
Of course there are many remedies for improving our mental health, but sometimes there are small and simple solutions to help improve our wellbeing.
改善心理健康的方法当然有很多，但有时候一些微小又简单的办法就能帮我们提升幸福感。
It’s something the BBC TV programme Easy Ways to Live Well has been looking at. It suggested several ‘health hacks’ which the programme’s presenters tried and gave their ‘seal of approval’.
英国广播公司的电视节目《健康生活小妙招》就关注了这类方法，节目推荐了几个“健康小窍门”，主持人亲自试过之后都给予了认可。
And maybe they could help us too.
或许这些方法也能帮到我们。
Firstly, to tackle putting on weight and to cut the calories, the programme found sniffing peppermint stops our craving for a snack.
首先，针对体重增加和热量摄入的问题，节目发现闻薄荷的气味能抑制我们想吃零食的欲望。
Presenter, chef and writer Hugh Fearnley-Whittingstall says “a scientific theory called ‘mutual competition’ shows that a strong smell can distract our brain from the food we’re thinking about.”
主持人、同时也是厨师和作家的休·费恩利-惠廷斯托尔表示：“有一种名为‘相互竞争’的科学理论认为，强烈的气味会分散大脑的注意力，让我们不再想着那些想吃的食物。”
If your addiction to your smartphone is getting you down, it’s suggested that turning your phone screen grey helps you reduce screen time because a black and white screen becomes less attractive to look at.
如果你因为沉迷手机而心情低落，不妨试试把手机屏幕调成灰色，这能帮你减少看手机的时间，因为黑白屏幕的吸引力会大大下降。
With recent studies showing our phones can make us 26% less productive and increase our stress, it seems like a no-brainer to try this ‘dim’ idea.
近期研究表明，手机会让我们的工作效率降低26%，还会增加压力，所以试试这个“昏暗”的办法显然是明智之举。
Fancy a swim in ice-cold water?
想试试在冰水里游泳吗？
Well, the BBC programme found a daily dip in freezing water gets you used to the stress of doing it and therefore prepares you for other life stresses.
英国广播公司的节目发现，每天泡一泡冰水能让身体适应这种压力，从而为应对生活中的其他压力做好准备。
And another way to ‘chill out’ is to leave your smartphone at home, immerse yourself in a forest, and breathe in the fresh air.
另一种放松身心的方法是把手机留在家里，全身心投入到森林中，呼吸新鲜空气。
Forest bathing is the perfect tonic for the stresses of urban life.
森林浴是缓解城市生活压力的绝佳良方。
Other life-improving ideas included things such as singing to reduce pain and fidgeting more to get away from our sedentary lives.
其他改善生活的方法还包括唱歌缓解疼痛、多活动身体摆脱久坐的生活状态等。
But whatever therapy we choose to adopt, it seems any change to our lifestyle can help improve our body and mind.
但无论我们选择哪种调节方式，只要改变生活习惯，似乎就能改善身心状态。